# AYODELE SALIMONU

Ikorodu, Lagos State +2348027168244 ayodele951@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using HTML, CSS, JQuery, PHP and JavaScript. Experience building products for desktop, phone and mobile app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

### SKILLS

- System development and administration
- Hardware and software installation
- Programming
- Troubleshooting and debugging
  Java experience
- · Problem-solving

- Mobile App Development (Android/iOS)
- · Web development
- Proficiency in HTML5, CSS and JavaScript

### WORK HISTORY

### LEAD WEB DEVELOPER | 08/2019 to Current

### How9ja - Ikorodu, Lagos State

- Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device and operating system compatibility
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design
- Spearheaded production of page content such as visuals and text copy to meet project specifications
- Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices
- Used programming capabilities in PHP, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed
- Took concepts and produced design mockups and prototypes to strengthen designs, enhance user experiences and improve site interactions
- · Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption

## WEB DEVELOPER INTERN | 12/2018 to 06/2019

### Andela, Epic Tower - Lagos, LA

- Designed and implemented web components across new and existing designs
- Worked on eCommerce maintenance and management for client websites
- Collaborated with project managers, testers, end-users, and distributors
- Studied basic project requirements with assigned technical lead and planned development strategies
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3
- Participated in project development through entire Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC)
- Supported web applications and web sites through database development

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN | 02/2018 to 11/2018

### IIHT - Surulere, Lagos State

- Maintained and upgraded products to deliver smooth-running systems
- Reviewed projects for compliance with specifications and quality standards
- Designed and tested client-server network components
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products

### EDUCATION

Olabisi Onabanjo University - Ago-Iwoye, Ogun State | Bachelor of Science Computer Science, 11/2019